# Gabriel Faustino Carvalho

Goiânia - GO - Brazil

Phone: +55 (62) 9.9176-6891 E-mail: faustinoknada@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/gabriel-faustino-carvalho



#### Goal

# Data Analyst

#### **Profile**

I'm Gabriel Faustino Carvalho, I help companies make profits and achieve their goals. I have a degree in Information Systems. I have more than 8 years of professional experience.

In my history I have experience and capacity for the roles of Data Analyst, ETL Developer, SQL Developer, Database Administrator, always working as a team with excellence and strong leadership.

I was able to learn and develop strategic skills that provide me with professional growth while maintaining the capacity for innovation.

I believe in great purposes by actively participating in completed projects and I am always willing to take on new challenges with the same success.

I need fulfillment at every moment, having the commitment to overcome obstacles with confidence, making things happen.

# **Education | Graduation | Qualification**

Information Systems – Estácio de Sá – 2024

English Advanced | Portuguese Native

### **Experience**

### GFT HARBOURVEST - May 2021 - April 2024

Role: ETL DEVELOPER/DATABASE DEVELOPER

Working with Datawarehouse SQL SERVER | Data analysis using SQL SERVER | ETL Packages development using Microsoft SSIS | Monitoring and execution ETL flow using Control-M and continua | Code version control using Git and Azure | Create database objects, Triggers, Procedures, Views and Functions | Scrum and Agile methodology | T-SQL development.

# INDIRA- GOIÁSPREV - Dec 2020 - May 2021

Role: DATABASE DEVELOPER

Create SQL SERVER databases, install and configure instances so that uses the best of the server in environment migrations | Data analysis using Python and T-SQL | ETL packages development using Microsoft SSIS | Create containers for databases MySQL, PostgreSQL, Mongodb, and SQL SERVER | Create dashboards using Microsoft Power BI | Create Database objects, Triggers, Procedures, Views and Functions.

#### **3DB SERVICOS DE TECNOLOGIA** – Apr 2019 – Dec 2020

Role: DATABASE ADMINISTRATOR

Automate indexing by creating scripts to defragment and recreate indexes that are highly fragmented in order to be successful in improving database performance | Create SQL SERVER databases and install and configure instances so that uses the best of the server in environment migrations.

Writing scripts and process to improve the performance of third-party applications | Monitor multiple instances and databases to verify costumer availability, performance and backup | Create databases mirror.

### ITECGYN INFORMÁTICA LTDA – Dec 2016 – Apr 2019

Role: DATABASE ADMINISTRATOR

Automate indexing by creating scripts to defragment and recreate indexes that are highly fragmented in order to be successful in improving database performance | Create databases SQL SERVER and install and configure instances so that uses the best of the server in environment migrations | Writing scripts and process to improve the performance of third-party applications | Bugs and queries fixing.

Monitor multiple instances and databases to verify costumer availability, performance and backups | Database design | Data analysis | Create database objects, Triggers, Procedures, Views and Functions

### Skills | Courses | Certificates

Skills: Data architecture | Installation | T-SQL | Go (Programing language) | Database Design | Writing | PostgreSQL | Microsoft Windows | Data Analysis | Version Control | MySQL | Database Administration | System support | Extract Transform Load (ETL) | Windows Servers | Agile Methodology | Microsoft SQL Servers | Computing | Indexing.

MongoDB | Control-M (Batch Scheduling | Certificates: MTA: Database Fundamentals - Conceitos básicos de banco de dados | Microsoft Certified Professional - Querying Data with Transact-SQL.

### **Competencies**

Ability to act as Data Analyst, ETL Developer, SQL Developer, Database Administrator.

Implementation, Management, Optimization, Monitoring of data recovery, storage and distribution | Source Mapping and definition of Data Ingestion strategy | Building Data Architectures | Development and Maintenance of Data Ingestion and Transformation Pipelines.

Monitoring of Data Ingestion and Distribution Processes | Automation of Data Update Routines | Collecting, organizing, preparing, analyzing and cleaning data from diverse sources | Use of advanced data analysis tools | Identifying trends, patterns and anomalies in data | Generate data visualizations, developing easy-to-understand dashboards that generate insights.

Translation of business needs into solutions and products aligned with the tools and that generate results | Design and development of new ETL solutions in addition to improvements and maintenance | Improvement in slow running jobs with the help of redesign and better ETL processes to meet the needs of the company | Unit tests.

Designing, modeling, developing and maintaining existing and new SQL database objects required for all business solutions | Development of new features for corrections | Planning the structure of projects and support activities | Technical assistance to junior developers regarding development tools.

### **Additional Information**

Soft skills: Emotional intelligence | Empathy | Teamwork | Active Listener | I work well under pressure | Problem analysis | Systems thinking.